（ヘルベルト）ウ　ウン。　ほう！　珍しいな。
Oh, this a surprise.
君が　ＰＯＧジャパンに顔を出すのは
いつ以来だ？
How long has it been since you've shown yourself at POG Japan?
たまった始末書でも
出しに来たか？
Are you here to submit all your written apologies?
私？　私は　屈辱の報告を
してきたところだ。
Me? I just had to make a very humiliating report.
ここまでは
小手調べだというのに。
Even though this is just the warm-up.
パズルを創造する神聖なる存在
ＰＯＧギヴァー。
The POG Givers, who create the puzzles, are close to divine existence.
その極東本部長ともあろう私が
ソルヴァーに敗北する訳がなかろうに。
There is no way that I, their leader, would lose to a Solver.
なあ？　まっ　次こそ
私のパズルが　大門カイトに→
Right?
Either way, my next puzzle will give
Daimon Kaito beautiful fear and death.
美しき恐怖と死を与えるだろう。
確実にな。　フフフフフッ。
I'm certain of it.
そこでだ。　次のパズルは
√学園に設置することにした。
I've decided to place the next puzzle in the Root Acedemy.
彼の最後には　うってつけだろう。
まさか　断りはしまいな？
It's the perfect place for it. He'll have no choice but to accept.
君のセクションが　特別権限を
持っているとはいえ→
Your section may have special rights, but my position is still higher.
階級は　私の方が上なのだからな。
分かったかね　解道バロン君。
Do you understand,
Kaido Baron?
（バロン）ウーン。　やれやれ。
しかたありませんね。
Oh my. I have no choice.
（ソウジ）で　許可したと。
拒否する理由もありませんから。
...and you allowed it?
I have no reason to deny them permission.
やっかいな人に
目を付けられましたね。
Troublesome people are just circling in.
これも試練…　ですか？
Is this training as well?
彼らには強くなってもらわねば
なりませんからね。
They need to get stronger.
「神のパズル」に挑める者
ファイ・ブレインの子供たち。
They, who can challenge the Divine Puzzle.
The children of the Phi Brain.
「彼らを成長させる」。
We must make them progress.
それが　我々ＰＯＧ特務育成機関
セクションΦの使命ですから。
That is our job, as the POG Special Education: Section Phi.
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
The Fallen Apple and the Path Ahead
Root Academy Fair
（ノノハ）じゃっ　じゃ～ん！
（カイト）うわ～っ？！　ノノハスイーツ？！
Nonoha sweets!
（キュービック）へぇ～！　マドレーヌ。
Ah, madeleine!
うちのクラスがやる「氷点下喫茶」の
目玉商品なんだよ。
It's the featured product of our class's Sub-Zero Café.
おいしそうだね！
食べて　食べて！
It looks delicious.
Have some!
要らない　要らない。
みんなは　学園祭　何するの？
I don't wanna.
What are you doing for the school fair?
（アナ）アナは　個展。
I'm having an exhibition.
I'm doing a presentation of my new invention: Okabe No. 3.
僕は　発明発表会。　オカベ君３号の。
天才って　出し物になるんだねぇ！
ギャモン君は？
So geniuses can do presentations.
And you, Gammon?
Mfhumnftemnd mnhomnfoumnse.
えっ？！
おば…　しき…。
Huh?
A haunted... house.
えっ？！　何？
お化け屋敷だ！　あぁ～！
Huh? What?
A haunted house!
なんで　学園祭なのに
ビビらなくちゃいけねえんだ？
Why does the school fair have to have scary stuff in it?
趣味悪いぜ！　あっ？！
This is just sickening.
そうだ　ノノハ！　お前のクラス
手伝ってやるぜ！
あっ　助かる！
I got it! I'll help your class, Nonoha.
That would be great! I need to go help out with the club booths.
私　いろんな部活の手伝いに
行かなくちゃいけないから。
１０時半から　バレー部のカレー屋でしょ。
10:30 - The curry shop of the volleyball team.
３５分からは
水泳部の水炊き屋で…。
10:35 - The boiled food restaurant of the swimming team.
４０分からは
演劇部の王子様役でしょ。
10:40 - I'm playing the prince in the drama club's play.
５０分からは　カバディ部の
かば焼き屋に→
10:50 - The grilled eel shop of the kabaddi club.
５５分からは　女子プロレス同好会の
試合でしょ。　あと１１時から…。
10:55 - The Women's Pro Wrestling Fanclub's tournament.
11:00 - The ramen shop of the soccer club.
Your memory is as insane as ever.
相変わらず　ムダに　いい記憶。
11:05 - Modeling for the photography club.
お前が居ねんなら　いいや。
こいつと　ツラ合わせてもな。
If you're not there, why would I go?
11:10 - The konjac balls shop of the lacrosse club.
To enjoy Kaito's wonderful presence?
あっ！　カイトも居ないよ。
大事なイベントもあるしねぇ。
Oh, Kaito won't be there either! He has an important event.
お前が　勝手に
エントリーしたんじゃねえか。
You entered without asking me!
何だよ？　「ルートボーイなんとか」って。
女装ミスコン！　男子限定！
What's that Root Boy something anyway?
A crossdressing beauty contest for boys!
はぁ～っ？！
カイト　女装似合いそうじゃない！
You'd be perfect for crossdressing, Kaito.
似合うんなら　アナの方だろう！
ふぇ？
If you want perfect, why not ask Ana?
ほ　ほう！
ダメ　ダメ　ダメ　ダメ　ダメ～っ！
ダメ！　アナは　ダメ！
No, no, no, no! Ana won't do!
かわいいけど　ダメ！　カイトが
変な気を起こしたら　大変だもん。
He's cute, but he won't do!
I don't want Kaito to have weird thoughts!
私は　カイトの女装が見たいの！
いやだ～！
I want to see you crossdressing, Kaito!
And I don't!
I'll enter too!
よし　俺も出る！
なんでだよ！
Why on earth would you?!
俺の女装
見せたいやつがいるのさ。
There's someone who I want to see me crossdressing.
This is beyond me!
（カイト・ノノハ）訳　分かんねえ！
Daimon.
（武田）大門君！
君も出場するとはね。
I didn't expect you to show yourself as well.
学園祭は　今までの屈辱を晴らす
絶好の機会になりそうだよ。
The school fair will be my ultimate chance to erase all the shame from before.
ま～た　てめえらか。
You guys again?
昨年の「ミス　ルートボーイ　コンテスト」。
努力賞の僕が　女装で君に勝ち！
I won the prize for effort in last year's Miss Root Boy Contest and this time, I'll win against you in crossdressing!
（相沢）さらに！　武田さんの新作
学園祭用特製ナンプレが　お前を倒す！
And Takeda's special school fair sudoku will be much more than you can handle!
（２人）まさに　パズル部の完全勝利！
（笑い声）
This will be a complete victory for the Puzzle Club!
（キュービック）
女装で勝って　うれしいの？
You're that happy to win at crossdressing?
相変わらず　不細工なナンプレ。
That's another boring sudoku.
お前らの女装みたいだな。
いっ　なぬ？！
I'm looking forward to your crossdressing.
What was that?!
じゃあ　ちょっと　僕が
（２人）部長！
変えてみようか？
Then how about I change it a bit?
Prez?!
軸川先輩！
Jikugawa?
はい。
Here.
心の声
こいつは　きれいだ。
This one's... beautiful.
（校内放送）「生徒会の軸川ソウジ会長
生徒会の軸川ソウジ会長…」。
Jikugawa Souji, president of the student council, I repeat,
Jikugawa Souji, president of the student council
is required at the school fair committee right away.
ふ～ん。　やれやれ。
生徒会長って　忙しいね。
Ah, the life of the student council president sure is busy.
心の声
不細工なナンプレを一瞬で
きれいなパズルに。
He made that clumsy sudoku so beautiful in just a second.
And he was the one who gave me this terminal as well.
心の声
そういや　この端末を
渡してきたのも…。
心の声
何なんだ？　あいつって。
I can't figure him out.
うんうん　おいしい　おいしい！
This is so good!
今年の学園祭も
盛り上がりそうだね。
This year's school fair will be great as well.
３度目の学園祭…。
My third one.
あれから２年か。
Two years since then.
回想
はっ　はっ　そ　そんな…。
Th-That can't...
僕には　ファイ・ブレインの資格無しか。
I don't have the possibility of the Phi Brain.
変な事を思い出しちゃったよ。
I remembered something strange.
きっと　リンゴみたいな
赤い夕日のせいだね。
I bet it's because of this sunset, red as an apple.
（校内放送）「いいかげんに
仕事に戻ってください。→
Come on, get back to work already!
軸川先輩！　軸川ソウジ～～っ！」。
Jikugawa! Jikugawa Souji!
Root Academy Fair
Candied apples
Frankfurter
（男子Ａ）うわぁ～～～！
Edison
Machine
Presentation
Okabe No. 3: Failure
で　どう？　お願い！　お願い！
How about this? I beg of you, please.
Haunted
house
（男子・女子）おっ　お化け～！
It's a monster!
（ギャモン）じゃあ！　行くぜよ！
Let's go!
見てな　ノノハ！
お前のために　俺は勝つ！
Just watch, Nonoha!
For you, I will win!
Girls' volleyball team
Serve the rice!
ごはん　どんどん　よそって！
Boiling in progress
They're fogging.
曇る。
（ヘルベルト）なかなか　盛況ではないか。
Well isn't this lively?
Thanks to this, I can act without anyone knowing.
おかげで　誰にも気づかれずに
事を運べるというものだ。
では　始めよう。
大門カイトに　美しき恐怖と死を…。
Let's begin then. Give Daimon Kaito beautiful fear and death.
（アイリ）カイト先輩　お肌きれい！
Kaito, your skin is so beautiful!
何で　俺が　こんな目に？
Why do I have to...
Kaito, do your best! I'll come cheer for you later!
カイト！　頑張ってね！
あとで応援に行くからね！
来んな！
ダメですよ。　じっとしてください。
Don't!
Don't move now, you have to stay still.
Next is the drama club!
次は　演劇部　演劇部！
うっ　あっ　いてててぇ！
Ouch...
あ～　ごめんなさい。　えっ？！
I'm sorry!
Kaito, you're so pretty!
先輩　すごくきれいです！
生き恥　さらしてねえか？
[TEL]
You mean "ridiculous"?
ハッキング成功と。
Hacking complete.
ノノハ君を使うとは　極東本部長とも
あろう人が　無茶をするね。
The new head of the Far East Division is really overdoing it.
これも　試練か。
Is this training as well?
Miss Root Boy Contest
Entry number three: Miss Takeda!
（アナウンサー）エントリーＮｏ．３　ミス武田！
（歓声）
起来！　起来！
（相沢）武田さ～ん！　ド・ハ・デ～！
Takeda! You're awesome!
（アイリ）どこ　行っちゃったのかな？
カイト先輩。
Where has Kaito gone?
こんなもんが　学園の中に…。
Why does it have to be on campus?
ノノハ！
Nonoha!
Welcome to the Sage Puzle, my princess.
（ヘルベルト）「ようこそ！
『賢者のパズル』へ　お姫様。→
ご覧のとおり　魔法にかけられた
王子様は眠りについてしまった。→
As you can see, your prince is bewitched and asleep.
彼を助けるためには
ドワーフの持つおいしいリンゴを→
You have to feed him the good apples of the dwarves to save him.
食べさせなければならない。→
だが　気をつけたまえ。
おいしいリンゴを持っているのは→
But be careful. Only the truth-teller dwarves, who only tell the truth, have good apples.
常に本当のことを言う
正直者グループのドワーフたちだけ。→
ウソしか言わないウソつきグループの
ドワーフたちが持っているのは→
The liar dwarves, who only lie, have poisoned apples.
毒リンゴだ」。
正直者と　ウソつき。
Truth-tellers and liars? Is this a logic puzzle?
論理パズルってやつか！
（ヘルベルト）「そのとおり。→
Exactly. This is a shapeless puzzle where you have to find the answer from what they say.
会話の中から　答えを導き出す
形のないパズル。→
それが　論理パズルだ」。
A logic puzzle indeed.
おいしいリンゴを　すべて
見つけることができれば→
If you can find all the good apples, your prince will be released.
王子様は解放される。
（ヘルベルト）「ただし　すべてが
燃えつきる前に出来ればだがね。→
That is, if you can do it before this place burns to the ground.
フフフッ」。
ふざけやがって！
You bastard!
では　始めよう。
Let's start then.
（ヘルベルト）「問題は　一度しか言わぬ。
よく聞きたまえ」。
You will only hear the problem once, so listen well.
（レッド　ドワーフ）ブラックが持っているのが
おいしいリンゴですよ。
Black has a good apple.
（オレンジ　ドワーフ）
俺様は　金塊を掘り当てたぜ。
I dug up a lump of gold!
Orange is in my group.
（イエロー　ドワーフ）
オレンジとは　同じグループなの。
（グリーン　ドワーフ）
山の天気は　変わりやすい。
きのうは大雨だったし。
The weather on the mountain is so whimsical. Yesterday, we had a huge rainstorm.
White isn't in my group.
（ブルー　ドワーフ）
ホワイトとは　同じグループじゃない。
（ブラック　ドワーフ）
グリーンとは　同じグループじゃねえぜ。
Green isn't in my group.
（ホワイト　ドワーフ）レッドが持っているのが
おいしいリンゴなり。
Red's apple is a good one indeed.
So, which ones are the good apples?
（ドワーフたち）
さあ　おいしいリンゴは　ど～れだ？
待ってろ！　ノノハ。　今　助ける！
Wait for me, Nonoha! I'll save you!
パズルタイムの始まりだ！
It's puzzle time!
リンゴを使った論理パズルね。
A logic puzzle with apples?
これは？！
This is...
どうなってやがる。
何度やっても　答えが見えねぇ！
What's going on? I can't find the answer no matter how many times I try.
もう一度　初めから考えるんだ。
Let's start again from the beginning.
Orange is in my group.
回想
（イエロー　ドワーフ）
オレンジとは　同じグループなの。
心の声
このイエローが
ウソつきグループだと仮定すると→
If Yellow is a liar, then it's a lie that Orange is in its group.
「同じグループ」って発言は　ウソ。
That means that Orange is in the truth-teller group.
心の声
オレンジは　イエローとは違う
正直者グループってことになる。
On the contrary, if Yellow is a truth-teller,
心の声
逆に　イエローが正直者だと仮定する。
そうすると
「同じグループ」って言葉は本当で→
then it's true that they're both in the same group.
オレンジは　イエローと同じ
正直者グループって事になる。
That means they're both truth-tellers.
Either way, Orange is a truth-teller.
心の声
どっちにしても
オレンジは　正直者グループ。
心の声
つまり　おいしいリンゴを
持っているのは　オレンジ。
Therefore, Orange has a good apple.
White isn't in my group.
回想
（ブルー　ドワーフ）
ホワイトとは　同じグループじゃない。
Following the same method as earlier,
心の声
さっきの考え方でいけば→
ブルーが　ウソつきグループなら
ホワイトは　ウソつき。
if Blue is a liar, then White is a liar too.
心の声
逆に正直者だとしても
ホワイトは　ウソつき。
And if Blue's a truth-teller, White is still a liar.
Either way, White is a liar.
心の声
どっちにしても
ホワイトは　ウソつき。
心の声
持っているのは　毒リンゴだ。
It has a poisoned apple.
Green isn't in my group.
（ブラック　ドワーフ）
回想
グリーンとは　同じグループじゃねえぜ。
心の声
同じ理屈で
グリーンも　ウソつきグループ。
Same logic, Green is a liar too.
（ホワイト　ドワーフ）レッドが
回想
持っているのが　おいしいリンゴなり。
Red's apple is a good one indeed.
心の声
さっき　ホワイトが
ウソつきグループだと分かった。
White is a liar, so this is a lie too.
心の声
だから　この言葉はウソ。
レッドの持っているのは　毒リンゴだ。
Red has a poisoned apple.
回想
（レッド　ドワーフ）ブラックが持っているのが
おいしいリンゴですよ。
Black has a good apple.
心の声
レッドも　ウソつきグループ。　だから
ブラックが持っているのも　毒リンゴ。
Red is a liar, so Black has a poisoned apple.
心の声
つまり　ウソつきグループは→
Which means that the liars are Red, Green, Black, and White.
レッド！　グリーン！　ブラック！　ホワイトで！
毒リンゴを持っている。
They have the poisoned apples.
And the good apples belong to Orange and...
心の声
そして　おいしいリンゴを
持っている正直者は　オレンジと…→
うっ…　やっぱり分からねぇ。
I don't know.
If there's only one, then it's Orange's.
心の声
おいしいリンゴが　１つならば
答えは　オレンジが持っているリンゴ。
心の声
３つならば　オレンジ　イエロー
ブルーの持っている３つ。
If there's three, then it's the apples of Orange, Yellow, and Blue.
心の声
だが　２つだとしたら…。
But if there's two...
心の声
おいしいリンゴは　いくつあるんだ？
How many good apples are there?
Without knowing that, I can't choose an answer!
心の声
それが分からねえと
答えを１つに絞り込めねぇ！
くっ！　時間が　ねえってのに！
I'm running out of time!
何か　何か大切な情報を
見落としてねえか？
Am I missing something important?
（ヘルベルト）フン…　美しい炎だ。
Beautiful flames.
Be scared, overcome by fear, and die, Daimon Kaito.
おびえ　恐れ　そして死ぬがいい。
大門カイト。
（ロープが切れる音）
ノノハ！
Nonoha!
Dammit!
クソッ！
Why? Why can't I find the answer?
なぜ…　なぜ　答えが見えない？
No way, is this puzzle...
心の声
まさか　このパズル…→
...lacking some required information?!
必要な情報が
足りてねえんじゃねえか？
Exactly.
これは　ミノタウロス？！
The Minotaur?
「このパズルには　本来あるべき情報が
意図的に伏せられている？！→
Some of the required information for this puzzle is concealed.
ゆえに　パズルに介入し　元に戻す」。
Therefore, I'll intervene and return it.
何だと？！
What?!
Why would you, a POG Giver, do that?
ＰＯＧギヴァーのお前が　何で
そんなことをするんだ？！
A puzzle made
for the
sole purpose
of murder
is not
beautiful...
Right?
It's the Solver's mistake to not see the flaws of the puzzle.
パズルの不備を見抜けないのは
ソルヴァーのミス。
そう　言い訳をするつもりの
ようだね　本部長は。
That's what the Japanese chief would say as an excuse.
そんなもの　試練でもなければ
賢者のパズルですら　ないよ。
This isn't training... It's not even a Sage Puzzle!
Would you accept it?
（バロン）受け入れられませんか？
It's true that as a Solver, you didn't have the possibility of the Phi Brain.
確かに　ソルヴァーとしての君は
ファイ・ブレインの資格を持たなかった。
ですが　ギヴァーとなった君は
それゆえに　大きな可能性を得た。
But with that, you've been shown the path of a Giver, full of possibilities.
私は　そう考えています。
ん？！
That's what I believe.
What's essential to Sage Puzzles is the wish to seal some treasure,
賢者のパズルとは　本来
財を封印したいという思いと→
and the wish to give it to someone with the ability to obtain it.
才能ある者には　財を託したいと
いう願い。
相反する依頼者の意志が
込められたものでした。
It is meant to be a battlefield of the minds.
But the puzzles the POG makes nowadays
ですが　今ＰＯＧが作るパズルは→
パズルとも言えない
人殺しの道具となりつつある。
are not even puzzles, but merely tools for murder.
光と闇　希望と絶望　ギヴァーとソルヴァー
その両方を知る君ならば→
Light and dark. Hope and despair. Giver and Solver.
You know both sides and you can correct the Sage Puzzles
賢者のパズルを正し　いずれは
ファイ・ブレインの子供たちを→
and lead the children of the Phi Brain to the Divine Puzzle in the right way.
神のパズルまで　正しく導くことが
できるのではないか。
そう考えているのですよ。
That's what I truly believe.
こんな不完全なパズルに　おめおめと
殺させるわけにはいかないんだよ。
I can't let them kill you so shamelessly with this incomplete puzzle!
僕の願い。　僕の夢。
そして　僕の大事な後輩をね。
My wish. My dream. My dear underclassman.
おいしいリンゴ…　おいしいリンゴは…
全部で３個だ。
There are... There are a total of three good apples.
That was the missing information!
それが　あるべき情報か！
それなら　答えが見える。
Now I know the answer!
The truth-teller dwarves are...
正直者のドワーフは
オレンジ！　イエロー！　ブルー！
Orange, Yellow, and Blue!
Their three apples are the good ones!
こいつらが持ってる３つが
おいしいリンゴだ！
Correct!
（ドワーフたち）正解！
Nonoha!
ノノハ！
バ　バカな！　パズルに介入しただと？！
W-What?! Someone intervened?! Who the hell?!
一体　誰が？　フッ…　まあ　いい。
No matter.
すでに　手遅れだ。
It's already too late.
うっ。　時間が　かかりすぎたか。
Did I take too much time?
あっ？！　クソッ！
Shit!
間に合ってよかった！
あっ？！
I'm glad we made it.
フフッ。　大切な後輩に　何かあったら
一大事だったよ。
I was worried something might happen to my dear underclassman.
なぜだ？　なぜ　死ななかった？！
Why?! Why didn't he die?!
完璧な作戦だったというのに！
私の計画を邪魔しおって。
How dare they interfere with my perfect plan!
何者だ？　こいつらは！
（バロン）ファイ・ブレインの子供たちですよ。
Who the hell are they?!
The children of the Phi Brain.
あっ。
さて　そろそろ学園祭もフィナーレ。
Now then, the school fair is nearing its finale.
ここからは
学生たちだけの時間です。
I'm going to spend some time with my students.
Please be careful as you leave, Chief.
気を付けて　お帰りください。
本部長。
ぐっ！　うっ。　ウン。
フ　フン。
This is my Okabe No. 3!
さすが　僕の作ったオカベ君３号
大成功だね！
It's a great success!
Failure
Great success
いつの間に　こんなものが
建ってたんだろうね。
I wonder when they built this.
It was the POG.
ＰＯＧだよ。
おや　それは大変だ。
Wow, that's terrible!
でも　解放したんだよね　パズル。
But you solved the puzzle, didn't you?
Kinda.
まあな。
うっ　う～ん！　あぁ。　あ～。
Nonoha!
ノノハ！
ミス　ルートボーイ　コンテストは？
The Miss Root Boy Contest?
大事なの　そっちかよ。
Is that all you care about?
（アナウンサー）
さあ　投票の結果が出ました。
The winner of this year's Miss Root Boy Contest is...
本年度　ミス　ルートボーイコンテストの
優勝者は…。
...none other than Miss Ana Gram!
（アナウンサー）
アナ・グラムさんに決定しました！
He didn't even enter!
そいつは参加してねえだろ！
ギャモン！
Gammon!
心の声
人を殺すためだけに
作られたパズル。
It was a puzzle made only to murder.
心の声
それを　ミノタウロスが正し
きれいなパズルにした。
The Minotaur corrected it and made a beautiful puzzle out of it.
心の声
分からねぇ。　何であいつが？
I don't get it. Why did he do it?
（女子Ｂ）
ああ？！　ノノハ　ここに居たんだ！
Ah, Nonoha, you were here!
Uh, yeah... I'm so sorry I couldn't help out.
ああ　そうだった！　みんな
手伝いに行けなくて　ごめん！
いいよ　いいよ！
生徒会長が手伝ってくれたしね。
It's fine, it's fine. The student council president helped out.
えっ？！　軸川先輩が？
Jikugawa did?
The prince role in our play.
演劇部の王子様役も。
（女子Ｃ）女子プロレス同好会の試合も。
The Women's Pro Wrestling Fanclub's tournament too.
（女子Ｄ）氷点下喫茶のマドレーヌも。
（３人）全部　手伝ってくれたの。
And the madeleine for the Sub-Zero Café as well.
He helped out with everything.
軸川先輩　すごい！
Jikugawa's amazing!
あいつも　よく分かんねぇ。
I don't get him either.
（バロン）
ずいぶん　無茶をしたものです。
You really worked hard, didn't you?
You hacked the chief's terminal and intervened in the puzzle.
本部長の端末へのハッキング。
パズルへの介入。
いずれも　ＰＯＧ憲章に
抵触する行為ですよ。
Both are actions that violate the charter of the POG.
本部長の作ったパズルが　ＰＯＧ憲章に
反していたものですから。
The chief's puzzle violated the charter as well.
封じられた財もなく
封じた者の思いもない。
It had no sealed treasure nor any feeling to it.
ただ　人を殺すためだけのパズルは
賢者のパズルとは言えませんので。
You can't call a puzzle made solely to murder a Sage Puzzle.
君が　我がセクションのメンバーだと
バレたら　一大事なんですよ。
It would be terrible if they found out that you are a member of my section.
フ　フッ…　まあ　いいでしょう。
今回の件は　不問とします。
But it's all right. I'll overlook this incident.
あとの処理は　こちらで。
ありがとうございます。
I will handle the rest.
Thank you very much.
しかし　見事な　お手並みでした。
But, you did it wonderfully.
さすが　ニュートンの称号を持つに
ふさわしい。
As expected from the one who holds the title of Newton.
彼の称号を頂いたからには　リンゴを
使ったパズルを悪用させるわけには→
Bearing his title, I can't let a puzzle with apples be so terribly misused.
いきませんからね。
助かります。
I am happy I have such a diligent student council president.
あなたのように　まじめで
優秀な生徒会長がいてくれると。
恩返しですよ。　ギヴァーとして　僕を
生き返らせてくれた学園長→
I'm just repaying my debt to you, Principal,
who gave me another life as a Giver. And...
あなたへの…。　それに　今の
この立場　嫌いじゃないんですよ。
I actually like this position.
僕の育てたソルヴァーが
神のパズルを解放する。
I might be able to see the Solvers I'm raising unseal the Divine Puzzle.
その瞬間に　立ち会えるかも
しれないんですから。
「彼らをファイ・ブレインへと導く…」。
Lead them to the Phi Brain.
それが　僕たちセクションΦの
使命ですよね。
That is our job as Section Phi, isn't it?
（バロン）そうですね。
Indeed.
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.